Contact

8000186647 (Mobile) kharanshuparekh@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kharanshuparekh-226620ba (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Customer Service Microsoft Excel Microsoft Office

Certifications

Introduction to Machine Learning-Duke University

SQL - MySQL for Data Analytics and Business Intelligence

Adobe InDesign CC - Essentials Training

Getting Started with AWS Machine Learning

R for Data Science: Data Visualization

KHARANSHU PAREKH

R&D Manager | Data Analyst Mandvi

Summary

An admirer of aesthetics turned Electrical Engineer turned Solar Professional, working as a Assistant manager in the R&D department of solar cell manufacturing facility of Adani. A dynamic professional with 5 years of experience in process setup, commissioning, ramp up, new product development, factory digitalization and automation.

Experience

Adani Solar 5 years 7 months

Assistant Manager (R&D) April 2021 - Present (11 months) Mundra

Senior Research And Development Engineer March 2019 - March 2021 (2 years 1 month) Mundra, Gujarat, India

Responsibilities and Projects while I was serving R&D department as a Sr. Engineer.

</> PERC Project: - I worked closely with German scientist from RCT and helped them in conducting various initial level trials for product establishment during process commissioning stage of the plant. Worked on various issues and critical aspects during product development phase such as Scratches, Annealing, Rear-Stack optimization, Process Flow, Machine effective downtime, formation of bow due to thermal stress, colour variation, protuition etc.

- I have extensively worked on LASER patterns to fetch maximum efficiency from rear passivation. Worked on German and Chinese make machineries (INNOLAS and DR LASER)

</> PERC+ with SE (PERC Bifacial) Project: - To further enhance efficiency of PERC cells, we have introduced Selective Emitter (SE) process and I was solely responsible for LASER optimization for Front as well as Back (LCO). I was pivotal in installation and commissioning of SE tool, LCO tool and High Precision (HP) camera at metallization stage for alignment and fiducial detection.

Senior Process Engineer January 2017 - March 2019 (2 years 3 months) Mundra, Gujarat, India

I had an opportunity to work along with industries smartest brain during my tenure as a Senior Engineer in Adani. Upon confirmation, I joined Process and Quality department with a responsibility of looking after various processes incorporated in solar cell manufacturing.

I worked along with Chinese, European and Italian engineers during process commissioning and ramp-up phase. I had an opportunity to witness the first ever multi-crystalline solar cell produce in the giant 1.2GW facility.

I feel proud to be part of the member of Process and R&D department over the span of my tenure as Sr. Engineer.

As a Process engineer, I was majorly looking after the health of the entire process and have been taken several improvement activities to enhance overall efficiency of the solar cell.

- Worked on various aspects of Thermal process such as Diffusion and PECVD to fetch maximum overall gain from the existing process.
- I along with my team was responsible of carrying out various improvement trials to uplift the overall plant yield.
- I was also responsible of training new joiners by providing them necessary technical, operational and safety related information before they actually work on shopfloor.

In the year of 2018, I joined R&D department to work on ambitious project of PERC and Bifacial(n-PERT) with a capacity of 300MW in total. Over the period of 2 years, we have established stable process flow and delivered product to management successfully.

Graduate Engineering Trainee August 2016 - January 2017 (6 months) Mundra, Gujarat, India

Started corporate journey with Adani Solar in the year of 2016 as a Graduate Engineer Trainee.

Being a proud member of the first GET batch of the company, I was privileged to witness and be part of the construction phase of the factory, establishment of various utility functions, machine movement, installation and process commissioning of the 1.2 GW solar cell and module manufacturing facility of the Adani group.

I have been assigned various task and responsibilities during my GET phase.

- I was pivotal in establishment of the high-tech Process Laboratory filled with various metrological instrument utilized in solar cell manufacturing such as Spectrophotometer, 3D-Microscope, Ellipsometer, Shunto meter, Life-time tester, EL tester, Rsheet measurement tool etc.
- I have been assigned to educated and trained upcoming operator batches while plant commissioning was in-progress. I along with my team have trained more than 1000 people over the span of 4-months.
- I was part of the team responsible to prepare Work-Instructions, SOPs, MQPs by refereeing several literature and best industrial practices.

ShapeAl
Data Analyst
July 2021 - Present (8 months)

The Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda Student Coordinator of Training and Placement Cell April 2015 - April 2016 (1 year 1 month)

As a Coordinator of Training and Placement Cell for Department of Electrical Engineering I was instrumental in inviting and conducting campus interview drive for numerous multinational companies for new graduate recruitment.

My team was successful in conducting about 25 on-campus interviews wherein more than 80 students were placed equivalent to 90% of class strength.

Companies included Linde, Larsen and Toubro, Tata Motors, Tata Consultancy, Accenture Inc., Adani Ports, Adani Solar, BASF, Reliance Industries, Jacobs Engineering, CEAT, Tata Technologies, L&T Tech Services, Infosys, and many more.

Paramarsh - Ideas Infinite Event Coordinator August 2012 - October 2015 (3 years 3 months) Vadodara Area, India

PARAMARSH is a national level non-technical event and biggest of its kind in western subcontinent of India

- (2012) Associated as 'Helping Volunteer', I have been given task to provide inputs to various events organized by PARAMARSH.
- (2013) Worked as a 'Volunteer' with other 40 team members where I have been assigned to design various Business, Art, Treasure hunt and physical activity related events from conception to implementation.
- (2014) Acted in capacity of an 'Organizer' of an event where we were handling team of 50 volunteers and also prepare roadmap of upcoming events (2015) I was among 5 proud 'Co-Ordinator' who is responsible of leading team of 70 enthusiastic students. Played pivotal role in important decision making and budgeting of a national level event.

Majorly in PARAMARSH, I was looking after 5 departments.

- (1) EVENT DESIGNING- where I was involved in designing the business-related event (BizMantra) to scrutinize the business skills of participants, one Physical task related event(F4) and one recreational event called Wrackreation.
- (2) DECORATION where we worked on different 3D,2D models, paintings and large size posters/banners related to our theme.
- (3) MEDIA RESPONSE It was my duty to write articles about different activities and updates of upcoming events, concerts and guest lectures for local newspapers and engage them during 3 days of our event including arranging conferences before concert with artists. I was looking after both digital and print media.
- (4) DESIGNING -I was part of the team responsible for graphic designing of various accessories and event related stuffs such as Event posters, fliers, sponsor banners, merchandise, souvenirs, online propagation posters, t-shirts, etc.
- (5) ONLINE PROPAGATION I was part of the team handling various official social media platforms and also, we were responsible to engage people through online propagations and events.

Page 4 of 5

Education

The Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda Engineer's Degree, Electrical Engineering · (2012 - 2016)

Zenith High School · (2001 - 2012)

kharanshuparekh@gmail.com

Vadodara, Gujarat, IND

+91 8000186647

S +91 000010002

♂ 27 years

PROFILE

A dynamic professional with **5+ years of experience** in Solar PV project installation, commissioning, process set-up, , ramp up, new product development, market research, data analysis, documentation, factory digitalization and automation.

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- MS Office Package
- Excel VBA
- Python
- R
- Power BI
- MySQL
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Visual Studio
- CorelDRAW
- Figma
- Cinema 4D

Graduation